

Ronny Rook

Freelance frontend developer | 29 years, Amsterdam ronnyrook.nl | github.com/rnnyrk

Having worked mostly in digital agencies his whole career, I had the chance to work with a lot of different technologies, stacks and clients. My expertise lies with React and React Native which I have both used to create amazing applications. From small apps to a big crypto platform.

I consider myself a proactive developer which can communicate well with both developers and clients. I have experience in taking decisions, taking the lead and working closely with clients.

Experience

iO Consultancy

Senior Frontend Developer & Consultant / 2023

As a senior frontend developer I've been used the help big clients professionalize and improve their products.

Stedin - stedin.net

Being one of The Netherlands biggest energy suppliers and energy-net maintainers

- Migrating to Turborepo
- Azure Pipelines
- · Creating a design system with Storybook
- Rewriting and optimising the codebase for performance improvements

Label A

Frontend Innovation Lead / 2021 - 2023

As an innovation lead I got the ability to push the frontend craft, engineers and tech stack to the next level by doing things like:

- Migrating 15 frontend developer from Javascript to Typescript
- Transition the team to NextJS
- · Introduced testing with React Testing Library
- Public Typescript presentation and workshop
- Public presentation about web performance

Label A

(Senior) Frontend Developer / 2018 - 2023

Being a developer within Label A made me do amazing projects and gave me a lot of opportunities to excel for great clients in an agile way of working. A selection of the projects:

Amdax - amdax.com/nl

Stretching over more than a year, we've build a complete crypto platform from scratch. Taking the roles as frontend developer and project lead.

- Implementing user management and authentication with Auth0
- · Biometrics login via web APIs
- Developed the trading, staking, savings and other various crypto finance features
- Integrated Buckaroo for payments
- Implemented localization with Lokalise
- Writing unit (React Testing Library) and end-to-end tests (Cypress)

Nationale Nederlanden - zelf.nl & electrifleet.nl

Worked on projects for two startups of NN. Both included their public website as well as an authenticated client environment. These applications were both fully built by leveraging AWS technologies as requested by NN: Lambda, S3, DynamoDB, Cognito.

- Building questionnaires flows
- Marketing websites with Gatsby
- Integrating Active Campaign
- End-to-end testing with Cypress

Alicia Insurances - alicia.insure/nl/

Alicia is Insurance as a Service platform which is used by companies like Knab who like to offer insurance to their customers. The web application is build as an white label service so companies can easily integrate their own branding.

- · Big interactive form for requesting insurance
- Creating ways of customising the platform per client (e.g. styling, own logo, etc.)

Fastis - fastis.nl

Fastis offers a platform for General Practitioners to schedule shifts. This complex application offered a lot of features for scheduling.

- Calendar view for seeing/planning the schedule
- · Authentication and user management
- · Accepting/declining changes in the schedule
- · Self-scheduling
- Admin screens for configuring the application

RoCycle - rocyclestudios.com

For RoCycle I've been working on both the application as well as the marketing website. The app is built with React Native and includes:

- Stripe payment integration
- Find lessons on a map
- · Book a lesson
- User management/Authentication

Muto - labela.nl/cases/muto

Similar to what a lot of car brands do, this web app allows customers to configure their electric bicycles:

- 3d viewing of the bicycle (build using ThreeJS and React Three Fiber)
- Selecting options to customize the bicycle
- Ordering the bicycle

BIT Students

Frontend Developer / 2016-2018

Part of the team as a designer and developer. Working on projects using techniques as VueJS, Polymer, ReactJS, iOS AR Kit and focussing on UX design by building users flows and wireframes.

IQ Media

Full stack Developer / 2012-2014

IQ-Media is a digital agency which builds websites and web applications for clients. Doing my first IT internship here, graduation from Deltion College and afterwards been working as an employee. Work was full stack with both PHP and Javascript.

Skills and techniques

As a frontend developer I got the chance to host multiple public workshops and presentations of various topics. Giving product demos to the client is also something I enjoy doing.

- React Native
- NextJS
- Firebase
- Prisma
- AWS
- Cypress
- GraphQL

- Webpack / Vite
- ThreeJS
- Supabase
- PostgresQL
- Framer Motion
- Turborepo
- Shopify

- Storybook
- Javascript
- Typescript
- CSS in JS
- Github Actions
- DevOps
- Redux

- PWA
- Jest / Vitest
- tRPC
- React Testing Library
- Auth0
- NodeJS
- Stripe

Education

Communicatie & Multimedia Design

Hogeschool van Amsterdam / September 2014 - 2018 Bachelor of Science

Interactieve Media Vormgeving

Deltion College Zwolle / September 2010 - 2014

Achievements

Golden Dot Awards 2018

Hogeschool van Amsterdam / July 2018
Golden Dot Awards. Award for the best student work of CMD Amsterdam in 2018. https://www.cmd-amsterdam.nl/gda-2018/nominaties-gda-2018/

Golden Dot Awards 2015

Hogeschool van Amsterdam / July 2015 Golden Dot Awards. Award for the best student work of CMD Amsterdam in 2015. https://www.cmd-amsterdam.nl

Member of the T500 2017 & 2018

The Next Web (TNW) / May 2017 & 2018

We're shortlisting 500 of the most ambitious, talented people in the Dutch digital scene. Holland's most gifted young talent in one single list. https://thenextweb.com/conference/t500

Medal of Excellence op Europees Kampioenschap vakwedstrijden

Euroskills / October 2014

Medal of Excellence ob the European Championship vocational skills October 2014 in Lille, Frankrijk. Category: webdesign worldskillseurope.org

Nederlands Kampioen vakwedstrijden

Skills Netherlands - February 2014

Winner Dutch Championship vocational skills. Category: webdesign skillsheroes.nl